Guide to the Monterey Jazz Festival Collection ARS.0018
Archive of Recorded Sound
Monterey Jazz Festival Collection
circa 1955-2015
Archive of Recorded Sound
Lyons, Jimmy
Gleason, Ralph J.
ARS.0018
126 box(es) [circa 126 linear feet]
The collection contains the archives of the Monterey Jazz Festival from 1958 to the present. It primarily consists of unpublished recordings and videos of festival concerts, interviews and panel discussions in various formats, including sound tape reels, sound cassettes, videotapes, and sound discs, many of which are also available as digital sound and video files. Also included are a variety of recordings received with the collection that are not recordings from the festival itself, but instead feature content connected to the festival in some way, such as studio recordings of artists who performed at the festival, demo tapes for artists wishing the perform at the festival, or various recordings relating to festival founder Jimmy Lyons in some way. Some books, photographs, posters, programs, and other miscellaneous papers can also be found in the archives. The collection adds material every year.
History
During its first twenty-five years, the Monterey Jazz Festival established a rich history and accumulated a sizeable body of important recordings featuring the most significant jazz musicians of their time. In 1984 the festival considered placing the tape recordings in the care of an established archive where they would be preserved in a secure and climate-controlled environment, cataloged, and made available for reference and research. Two years later, archivist Barbara Sawka accepted the collection for Stanford, and over subsequent years the festival continues to add each year's performances to the Stanford archive. As a whole, the festival's collection documents one of the premiere jazz institutions in the world, comprising over 1,500 sound and moving image recordings of live performances and interviews. A brief reflection of the Festival's first fifty years reveals the place of this archive as a rich resource in the study of jazz and jazz history.
Access
The media recordings in the Monterey Jazz Festival Collection and related documents, such as posters and programs, may only be accessed onsite at the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound. Archive staff can also direct you to additional material related to the festival and several published recordings of Monterey Jazz Festival performances that are currently available in libraries or for purchase.
The digital collection is available at http://collections.stanford.edu/mjf.
Database of unpublished recordings
More detailed information on individual unpublished concert recordings in the Monterey Jazz Festival Collection can be found in the following online database for the collection http://collections.stanford.edu/mjf.
Jazz; Music festivals -- California -- Monterey; Lyons, Jimmy; Monterey Jazz Festival; Gleason, Ralph J.
- Unpublished live recordings, 1956-2015; 105 item(s)
  - Festival recordings, 1956-2015; 99 box(es)
    Database of unpublished recordings
    More detailed information on individual unpublished concert recordings in the Monterey Jazz Festival Collection can be found in the following online database for the collection http://collections.stanford.edu/mjf. This database includes the item numbers used in the title fields in this part of the finding aid.
    Scope and contents
    Video and audio of live performances from the annual Monterey Jazz Festival. Also included are interviews, and news coverage.
    Arrangement note
    Boxes 77-78 have been withdrawn and their contents distributed to other boxes in the collection. Boxes 82-85 include preservation DVD access copies of original materials in the collection, and are therefore not included here.
    - 0013-0029; 0038, 1958-1960; 1 box(es) (Box 1)
    - 0001-0012; 0030-0054, circa 1958-1964; 1 box(es) (Box 2)
    - 0055-0056; 0101; 0112-0143, 1964-1970; 1 box(es) (Box 3)
    - 0057-0073, 1964-1965; 1 box(es) (Box 4)
    - 0074-0090, 1965-1966; 1 box(es) (Box 5)
    - 0091-0109, 1966; 1 box(es) (Box 6)
    - 0110-0111; 0153-0167, 1966-1971; 1 box(es) (Box 7)
    - 0144-0152; 0186-0189; 0212; 0218-0219; 0221-0222; 0226-0232; 0235-0238; 0249-0250; 0264-0265; 0273; 0276; 0279, 1970-1973; 1 box(es) (Box 8)
    - 0168-0183; 0185, 1971; 1 box(es) (Box 9)
    - 0188; 0190-0206, 1972; 1 box(es) (Box 10)
    - 0207-0211; 0213-0217; 0220; 0224-0226; 0233-0234; 0239-0240, 1972; 1 box(es) (Box 11)
    - 0241-0248; 0251-0260, 1950-1972; 1 box(es) (Box 12)
    - 0261-0263; 0266-0272; 0274-0275; 0277-0278; 0280-0283; 0289, 1973; 1 box(es) (Box 13)
    - 0290-0293; 0297; 0299-0300; 0302; 0308-0309; 0311-0312; 0314-0315; 0317; 0319-0322; 0324; 0327-0328; 0340; 0346; 0349-0350; 0354-0355; 0358; 0365-0372, 1973-1976; 1 box(es) (Box 14)
    - 0284-0288; 0294-0296; 0298; 0301; 0303-0307; 0310; 0313; 0316; 0318, 1973-1974; 1 box(es) (Box 15)
    - 0323; 0325-0326; 0329; 0331-0345; 0347, 1974-1975; 1 box(es) (Box 16)
    - 0348; 0351-0353; 0356-0357; 0359-0364; 0377-0384, 1975-1977; 1 box(es) (Box 17)
    - 0385-0402; 0404, 1977; 1 box(es) (Box 18)
    - 0403; 0405-0406; 0457-0471, 1977-1979; 1 box(es) (Box 19)
    - 0472-0489, 1979-1980; 1 box(es) (Box 20)
    - 0373-0376; 0407-0438, 1976-1979; 1 box(es) (Box 21)
    - 0439-0456; 0569; 0844-0853; 0876-0878; 0945-947, 1976-1982; 1 box(es) (Box 22)
    - 0490-0506, 1980; 1 box(es) (Box 23)
    - 0508-0523, 1980; 1 box(es) (Box 24)
    - 0524-0542, 1980-1981; 1 box(es) (Box 25)
    - 0543-0560, 1981; 1 box(es) (Box 26)
    - 0561-0568; 0570-0577; 0579, 1981-1983; 1 box(es) (Box 27)
    - 0580-0598, 1983; 1 box(es) (Box 28)
    - 0599; 0601-0617, 1983-1985; 1 box(es) (Box 29)
    - 0618-0636, 1985-1986; 1 box(es) (Box 30)
    - 0637-0654, 1986; 1 box(es) (Box 31)
    - 0655-0672, 1986-1988; 1 box(es) (Box 32)
    - 0673-0690, 1988-1989; 1 box(es) (Box 33)
    - 0691-0708, 1989-1990; 1 box(es) (Box 34)
    - 0709-0727, 1990-1991; 1 box(es) (Box 35)
    - 0728-0738; 0854-0861, 1977-1991; 1 box(es) (Box 36)
    - 0862-0875; 0879-0883, 1977-1978; 1 box(es) (Box 37)
    - 0884-0902; 0906, 1978-1979; 1 box(es) (Box 38)
    - 0903-0905; 0907-0911; 0914-0919, 1979-1980; 1 box(es) (Box 39)
    - 0912-0913; 0920-0931, 1980-1981; 1 box(es) (Box 40)
    - 0932-0944; 0948; 0950-0953, 1981-1983; 1 box(es) (Box 41)
    - 0949; 0954-0964; 0968-0973, 1983-1985; 1 box(es) (Box 42)
    - 0974-0978; 0983-0988; 1454-1461, 1958-1985; 1 box(es) (Box 43)
    - 1213-1222, 1967; 1 box(es) (Box 44)
    - 1223-1232, 1967; 1 box(es) (Box 45)
    - 0965-0967; 0979-0982; 1233; 1462-1473, 1958-1985; 1 box(es) (Box 46)
    - 0739-0790, 1992-1994; 1 box(es) (Box 47)
    - 0791-0843, 1994-1995; 1 box(es) (Box 48)
    - 1099-1122; 1154-1172; 1175-1182, 1965-1997; 1 box(es) (Box 49)
    - 1183-1212, circa 1993-1997; 1 box(es) (Box 50)
    - 1303-1322; 1324-1325; 1327-1330; 1374-1395, 1998-1999; 1 box(es) (Box 51)
    - 1397; 1428-1430; 1432-1441; 1443-1453; 1512-1518; 1520-1523; 1582-1594, 1999-2002; 1 box(es) (Box 52)
    - 1595-1601, 1979; 1 box(es) (Box 53)
    - 1645-1652; 1654-1669, 1982-2003; 1 box(es) (Box 54)
    - 1755-1773, 2005; 1 box(es) (Box 55)
    - 1602-1609, 1979; 1 box(es) (Box 56)
    - 1173-1174; 1323; 1326; 1519; 1670-1675; 1677-1684; 1699-1724, 1997-2004; 1 box(es) (Box 57)
    - 0223; 1620-1633; 1635; 1638-1644, 1956-1986; 1 box(es) (Box 58)
    - 1498-1511; 1538-1556, 2001-2002; 1 box(es) (Box 59)
    - 1613-1619, 1980; 1 box(es) (Box 60)
    - 1421-1427; 1474-1497, 1995-2001; 1 box(es) (Box 61)
    - 1557-1565; 1610-1612, 1980-2002; 1 box(es) (Box 62)
    - 1399-1403; 1404-1420, 2000; 1 box(es) (Box 63)
    - 1346-1373, 1999; 1 box(es) (Box 64)
    - 1091-1097; 1123-1149, 1996-1997; 1 box(es) (Box 65)
    - 1026-1045, 1983-1995; 1 box(es) (Box 66)
    - 1286-1302; 1332-1345, 1998-1999; 1 box(es) (Box 67)
    - 1254-1285, 1997-1998; 1 box(es) (Box 68)
    - 1150-1153; 1234-1253, 1991-1997; 1 box(es) (Box 69)
    - 1072-1090, circa 1989-1996; 1 box(es) (Box 70)
    - 1005-1025, 1978-1983; 1 box(es) (Box 71)
    - 1046-1048; 1057-1071, circa 1983-1993; 1 box(es) (Box 72)
    - 1049-1056, 1967-1978; 1 box(es) (Box 73)
    - 1000-1004, 1982; 1 box(es) (Box 74)
    - 0988-0997; 0999, 1975-1982; 1 box(es) (Box 75)
    - 0998; 1032; 1796-1808, 1982-2006; 1 box(es) (Box 76)
    - 2337-2344, 2006; 1 box(es) (Box 79)
    - 2328-2331, 2007; 1 box(es) (Box 80)
    - 2332-2336, 2008; 1 box(es) (Box 81)
    - 1892-1904; 1939, 2007-2008; 1 box(es) (Box 86)
    - 1940-1952, 2008; 1 box(es) (Box 87)
    - 1987-1998, circa 2009; 1 box(es) (Box 88)
    - 1999-2010, 2009-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 89)
    - 1980-1985; 2011-2038, circa 1978-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 90)
    - 2041-2044, 2009-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 91)
    - 1816-1828; 1872-1891; 1919-1929, 2006-2008; 1 box(es) (Box 92)
    - 1676; 1953-1954; 2051-2092, 2003-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 93)
    - 1524-1537; 1566; 1570-1572; 1574-1581, 2001-2002; 1 box(es) (Box 94)
    - 1685-1698; 1725-1729; 1731-1737; 1739-1754; 1774-1776, 2003-2005; 1 box(es) (Box 95)
    - 1777-1786; 1905-1918; 1930-1938; 1955-1966; 1974-1979; 2039-2040; 2045-2050, 2005-2009; 1 box(es) (Box 96)
    - 1634; 1834-1842; 1851-1859; 1398, 1958-1967; 1 box(es) (Box 97)
    - 0330; 0906; 1860-1871; 1967-1973; 1986; 2098-2113; 2116-2121; 2135-2140; 2142-2146; 2165-2166; 2183-2185; 2205-2207; 2209-2211; 2223-2226; 2250-2254; 2283-2284; 2297-2298, 1958-2008; 1 box(es) (Box 98)
    - 2147-2159, 2011; 1 box(es) (Box 99)
    - 2160-2164; 2168-2182; 2186-2195, 2011; 1 box(es) (Box 100)
    - 2197-2204; 2208; 2212-2222; 2227-2231, 2012; 1 box(es) (Box 101)
    - 2232-2249; 2255-2261; 2327, 1975-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 102)
    - 2262-2282; 2285-2296, circa 1995-2010; 1 box(es) (Box 103)
    - 1331; 2114-2115; 2122-2134; 2167; 2299-2302; 2304; 2321, circa 1958-1985; 1 box(es) (Box 104)
    - 2322-2324, circa 1995; 1 box(es) (Box 105)
    - 2345-2366, 2013; 1 box(es) (Box 122)
    - 2367-2388, 2014; 1 box(es) (Box 125)
    - 2389-2407, 2015; 1 box(es) (Box 126)
  - 50th Anniversary Tour recordings, 2008 June-July; 6 item(s)
    - Monterey Jazz Festival 50th Anniversary Tour: Reference Mix. Live at Purchase College, Purchase, NY., 2008 June 3; 2 optical disc(s) (cd-r) (Box 106)
      Satronen Sound
    - Monterey Jazz Festival 50th Anniversary Tour: Reference Mix. Live at The Tilles Center, Brookville, NY., 2008 July 3; 3 optical disc(s) (cd-r) (Box 106)
    - Monterey Jazz Festival 50th Anniversary Tour. Master multitrack files., 2008 March; 1 hard drive(s) [Maxtor USB external hard drive] (Box 81)
      Copies note
      Drive contents have been copied to SMPL preservation server: dpgThumper2.stanford.edu/pool0/ARS0025_mjf/2008-5
- Commercial recordings, 1958-2009; 38 item(s)
  Commercial recordings from the Monterey Jazz Festival on compact disc, LP, and videocassette.
  - Compact Discs, 1958-2009; 15 compact disc(s)
    - Corea, Clarke and White: Forever, 2009; 2 compact disc(s); Concord Records. CRE-32627-02. Published 2011. (Box 106)
      Disc 2, Track 10 - 500 Miles High, recorded at Monterey Jazz Festival, 2009 September 30.
      White, Lenny; Clarke, Stanley; Corea, Chick
    - Miles Davis Quintet: Live at the 1963 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1963 September 20; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30310. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      Williams, Tony; Carter, Ron; Miles Davis Quintet; Davis, Miles; Hancock, Herbie; Coleman, George; Lyons, Jimmy
    - Louis Armstrong: Live at the 1958 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1958 October 3; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30311. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      Armstrong, Louis; Barcelona, Danny; Kyle, Billy; Middleton, Velma; Herbert, Mort; Hucko, Peanuts; Young, Trummy
    - Thelonious Monk: Live at the 1964 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1964 September 20; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30312. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      Swallow, Steve; Rouse, Charlie; Riley, Ben; Monk, Thelonious
    - Shirley Horn: Live at the 1994 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1994 September 18; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30313. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Ables, Charles; Williams, Steve; Horn, Shirley
    - Dizzy Gillespie: Live the at the 1965 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1965 September 19; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30337. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      Big Black; Barron, Kenny; White, Chris; Moody, James; Gillespie, Dizzy; Collins, Rudy
    - Sarah Vaughan: Live at the 1971 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1971 September 19; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30351. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      Jazz at the Philharmonic Stars; Vaughan, Sarah; Mays, Bill; Magnusson, Bob; Cobb, Jimmy
    - Live at the Monterey Jazz Festival: Highlights Vol.1, 1958-1991; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30352. Published 2007. (Box 106)
      All Stars (Musical group: Louis Armstrong); Blade, Brian; Dave Brubeck Quartet; Dizzy Gillespie Sextet; Ford, Robben; Grenadier, Larry; Henderson, Joe; Krall, Diana; Miles Davis Quintet; Pat Metheny Trio; Thelonious Monk Quartet; Vaughan, Sarah; Witherspoon, Jimmy
    - Monterey Jazz Festival 50th Anniversary All-Stars, 2007 September 23; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30433. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Hodge, Derrick; Green, Benny; Scott, Kendrick; Moody, James; Blanchard, Terence; Freelon, Nnenna
    - Jimmy Witherspoon: featuring Robben Ford, 1959-1972; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30638. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Hawkins, Coleman; Ford, Robben; Hines, Earl; Herman, Woody; Witherspoon, Jimmy; Lewis, Mel
    - 50 years of Dave Brubeck, 1958-1985; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30680. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Brubeck, Dave
    - Tito Puente and His Orchestra: Live at the 1977 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1977 September 18; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30700. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Tito Puente Orchestra
    - The Best of Cal Tjader: Live at the Monterey Jazz Festival 1958-1980, 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30701. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Tjader, Cal
    - Art Blakey and the Giants of Jazz: Live at the 1972 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1972 September 16; 1 compact disc(s); MJF Records. MJFR-30882. Published 2008. (Box 106)
      Terry, Clark; Winding, Kai; Monk, Thelonious; Sitt, Sonny; Blakey, Art; McKibbon, Al; Eldridge, Roy
  - LP, circa 1958-1980; 22 12" vinyl disc(s)
    - Woody Herman: Live at Monterey, 1959 October 3; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Atlantic, 900441. Published 1982. First published 1960 as Atlantic, 1328. (Box 110)
      Tracklisting
      Four brothers; Like some blues man; Skoobeedoobee; Monterey apple tree; Skylark; The magpie.
      Herman, Woody
    - Woody Herman's Big New Herd at the Monterey Jazz Festival, 1959 October 3; 2 12" vinyl disc(s) [2 copies; 1 mono, 1 stereo]; Atlantic, 1328 (Mono). Atlantic, SD 1328 (Stereo). Published 1959-1960. (Box 110)
    - Woody Herman: Live at Monterey, 1959 October 3; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Atlantic, ATL 50236. Published 1976. Previously released as Atlantic, SD1328. (Box 110)
      Date note
      This recording claims that the contents were recorded 1960 March 15. However, this is a reissue of Atlantic, SD1328 which was recorded on 1959 October 3. This October date is also backed up by a later 1982 reissue of the same recording, Atlantic, 900441.
    - Forest Flower: Charles Lloyd at Monterey, 1966 September 18; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Atlantic, SD-1473. Published 1967. (Box 110)
      Forest flower - sunrise; Forest flower- sunset; Sorcery; Song of her; East of the sun.
      This recording claims that the contents were recorded 1960 March 15. However, this is a reissued of Atlantic, SD1328
      Lloyd, Charles
    - Evolution of the blues song, 1960; 2 12" vinyl disc(s) [2 copies; 1 mono, 1 stereo]; Columbia, CL 1583 (Mono). Columbia, CS 8383 (Stereo). Published 1960-1961. (Box 110)
      Introduction; Amo; Some stopped on de way; Swing low, sweet chariot; New Orleans; I had my share; Please send me someone to love; Sufferin' blues; That's enough; Aw, gal; See see rider; Jumpin' with Symphony Sid; Sun gonna shine in my door; W.P.A. blues; Sometimes I feel like a motherless child.
      Hendricks, Jon
    - Billie Holiday: at Monterey, 1958, 1958 October 5; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Black Hawk Records, BKH 50701. Published 1986. (Box 110)
      Ain't nobody's business but my own; Willow weep for me; When your lover has gone; God bless the child; I only have eyes for you; Good morning heartache; Them there eyes; Billie's blues; Oh, what a little moonlight can do; Trav'lin lights; Lover come back to me.
      Khan, Eddie; Holiday, Billie; Waldron, Mal; Berk, Dick
    - John Handy: Recorded Live at the Monterey Jazz Festival, 1965; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Columbia, CS 9262. Published 1965-1966. (Box 110)
      Spanish lady; If only we knew.
      Handy, John
    - Woody and Friends, 1979 September 15; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Concord Jazz, CJ-170. Published, 1981. (Box 110)
      Caravan; I got it bad and that ain't good; Count down; Better git it in your soul; Woody'n you; What are you doing the rest of your life; Manteca.
      Gillespie, Dizzy; Getz, Stan; Herman, Woody; Hampton, Slide; Shaw, Woody; Woody Herman’s Thundering Herd
    - 1959 Monterey Jazz Festival, 1959 October 2; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Everest Records, FS 239. Published circa 1960. (Box 110)
      Ain't nobody's business; When I been drinkin'; No rollin' blues; Good rockin' tonight; Big fine girl.
      Witherspoon, Jimmy; Eldridge, Roy; Hawkins, Coleman; Herman, Woody; Hines, Earl; Lewis, Mel; Webster, Ben
    - Jimmy Witherspoon at the Monterey Jazz Festival, 1959 October 2; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Hifijazz, J 421. Publication date unknown. (Box 110)
      No rollin' blues; Good rockin' tonight; Big fine girl; Ain't nobody's business; When I been drinkin'.
      Hines, Earl; Webster, Ben; Witherspoon, Jimmy; Herman, Woody; Hawkins, Coleman; Lewis, Mel; Alley, Vernon; Eldridge, Roy
    - More Sorcery: Gabor Szabo, 1967; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Impulse, AS-9167. Publication date unknown. (Box 110)
      Los Matodoros; People; Corcovado; Lucy in the sky with diamonds; Comin' back; Spellbinder.
      Recording locations
      Side 1 (Los Matodoros; People; Corcovado) recorded a Jazz Workshop, Boston, 1967 April 14-15. Side 2 (Lucy in the sky with diamonds; Comin' back; Spellbinder) recorded at the Monterey Jazz Festival, 1967 September 17.
      Szabó, Gábor
    - Mingus at Monterey, 1964 September 20; 2 12" vinyl disc(s) (Box 110)
      Duke Ellington medley: I've got it bad, In a sentimental mood, All too soon, Mood indigo, Sophisticated lady, A train; Orange was the color of her dress, then blue silk; Meditations on integration.
      Publication details
      Fantasy, JWS 001-JWS 002.
      Mingus, Charles
    - Night Flight, circa 1960-1970; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Pacific Jazz, PJ-10101. Date of publication circa 1960-1970. (Box 110)
      Tin tin deo; I'm in the mood for love; Night flight; Our man Flint; Seesaw; Batucada surgiu; 17 mile drive; A patch of blue; Latin lady; Blues for a debutante; Sweets for my sweet; Wild chestnuts.
      Moody, James; Monterey Jazz Festival. Orchestra; Fuller, Gil
    - Gil Fuller and the Monterey Jazz Festival Orchestra, 1965; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Pacific Jazz, T-90458. Published circa 1965. (Box 110)
      Man from Monterey; Angel City; Love theme from the Sandpiper; Groovin' high; Be's that way; Big Sur; Moontide; Things are here.
      Monterey Jazz Festival. Orchestra; Gillespie, Dizzy; Fuller, Gil
    - Bola Sete at the Monterey Jazz Festival, 1966 September; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Verve, V6-8689. Published circa 1966. (Box 110)
      Medley: Manha de carnaval, A felicidade, Samba de Orfeu; Soul samba; Flamenco.
      Bola Sete
    - Jazz Monterey, 1958-1980; 2 12" vinyl disc(s); Palo Alto Records, PA8080-2. Published 1984. (Box 110)
      The sticks (The Cannonball Adderley Quintet); Green Dolphin Street (Toots Thielemans); Body and soul (Woody Herman Orchestra); Isotope (Joe Henderson Quartet); All of you (Jon Hendricks); Doxie (Jimmy Giuffre Three); The Jampfs are coming (Johnny Griffin); Two bass hit - Ad hoc jam (Buddy Rich and his Orchestra with Dizzy Gillespie); God bless the child (Clark Terry); You can depend on me (Joe Williams with Prez Conference); I remember Clifford (Benny Golson); Remembering (Joanne Brackeen Trio).
      Williams, Joe; Brackeen, Joanne; Terry, Clark; Thielemans, Toots; Herman, Woody; Rich, Buddy; Henderson, Joe; Hendricks, Jon; Golson, Benny; Griffin, Johnny; Gillespie, Dizzy; Giuffre, Jimmy; Adderley, Cannonball
    - Concerto for Herd, 1967 September; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Verve, V6/8764. Published circa 1968. (Box 110)
      Concerto for herd: First movement, Second movement, Third movement; Big Sur echo (Don Rader, composer); The horn of the fish (Bill Holman, composer); Woody's boogaloo (Kenny Ascher, composer).
      Woody Herman’s Thundering Herd; Herman, Woody
    - The Real Ambassadors, 1962; 1 12" vinyl disc(s); Columbia, OL 5850. Published 1962. (Box 110)
      Everybody's comin'; Cultural exchange; Good reviews; Remember who you are; My one bad habit; Summer song; King for a day; Blow Satchmo; The real ambassador; In the lurch; The moment worth years; They say I look like God; Since love had its way; I didn't know until you told me; Swing bells - Blow Satchmo - Finale.
      Brubeck, Dave; Armstrong, Louis
  - Videocassettes, 1958-1998; 1 videocassette(s)
    - Monterey Jazz Festival: 40 Legendary Years, 1958-1998; 1 videocassette(s); Warner Home Video. 36494. Published 1998. (Box 106)
- Non-Festival recordings, circa 1955-1979; 37 audiotape reel(s)
  - To Jimmy Lyons from Don Lanphere and Jon Pugh. Wenatchee, WA 98801., 1979 November 19; 1 audiotape reel(s) [Quarter inch tape] (Box 107, Reel 1)
    Audio message from Saxophonist Don Lanphere to Jimmy Lyons. Recalls his father sending him tapes of Lyon's radio broadcasts and his 1959 MJF performance with Woody Herman. Tape contains musical selections that trumpet player John Peters recorded in his home studio. Tunes are interspersed with Lanphere comments.
    Additionally, Lanphere tells Lyons of his recent (1979) gigs and upcoming events. Also includes performances of Lanphere with John Peters and Central Washington State Jazz Band.
    Peters, John; Central Washington State Jazz Band; Lanphere, Don
  - Red Norvo Trio at Sunset. Disco #1., undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [Quarter inch tape, 7.5 ips] (Box 107, Reel 2)
    Lover come back to me; Perdido; Tenderly; Rosetta; In the midst of time; Exactly like you; Body and soul; I get a kick out of you; Dancing on the ceiling; My heart stood still; I surrender dear.
    Disco # 1 is written in different ink over the information for the Red Norvo Trio set.
    Red Norvo Trio
  - Ella Fitzgerald at Sunset Auditorium, 1956 September 1; 1 audiotape reel(s) [Quarter inch tape, half track, 7.5 ips, mono] (Box 107, Reel 3)
    Intro by Jimmy Lyons; Little boy; It might as well be spring; Same old Saturday night / Dont get around much anymore; Hard hearted Hannah - The vamp of Savannah, GA; I cant give you anything but love, baby; Cry me a river; Love and marriage; Lullaby of Birdland; I've got a crush on you; Sixteen tons; The tender trip; Air mail special; Trio instrumental; This cant be love; Someone to watch over me; Cow cow boogie; Angel eyes; That old black magic; How high the moon; Roll em pete; My funny valentine; Autumn leaves; A tisket, a tasket; St. Louis blues.
    Abney, Don; Mills, Jackie; Fitzgerald, Ella; Alley, Vernon
  - Excerpts from Concert by the Sea - Erroll Garner, 1955 September 19; 1 audiotape reel(s) [Quarter inch tape] (Box 107, Reel 4)
    Mambo Carmel; Teach me tonight; three clips ending with Will you still be mine; I cover the waterfront; Bernie's tune; How could you do a thing like that to me; Laura; Red top; April in Paris.
    Additional content